Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
Great Detective Conan
Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi
This is... a bomb?!
Eh!?
Ah! There's already
less than a minute left!
There's no mistake about the time.
Let's see, let's see... Ah! Was this that
occasion when those two came from Osaka?
Still, there are several candidates
for the keyword to this one...
Shin'ichi, say, are you really going home?
That High School Student Detective
like you is coming from Osaka.
- Don't you want to meet him?
- Fool!
Anyhow, isn't Sherlock Holmes there
just an ordinary detective?
So I'm really...
"Osaka High School Student Detective - Hattori Heiji"
...not interested.
Saying that again.
"Heiji's Childhood Friend - Toyama Kazuha"
Truth is, ya are worried 'bout him.
Am not!
I wouldn't even know his face.
More importantly,
where's the bus to Teitan High School?
Even so, it's been going around recently that
"East is Kudoć, West is Hattori"...
Huh?!
Huh? When you say that, say,
"West is Hattori, East is Kudo"!
Got that?
"West is Hattori, East is Kudo."
Get the order straight!
The order!
See, you are worried about him!
Am not, IDIOT!
Geez, you.
What would I be doing worrying 'bout
some good-fer-nothin' anyhow?
He's been racking up cases
left and right here in Tokyo.
He's badder than you in Tokyo,
so you'd better keep up your guard.
Fool!
Who on earth's gonna
raise the tension here in Tokyo?
More importantly Heiji, you've got
that lucky charm on you, right?
When you forgot the charm that once,
ya got seriously hurt during the match.
Kazuha, take these!
Heiji?!
Wait right there, ya brat!
Wait!
Hey! Purse snatcher!
Wait up! Come here!
What was that?
At a time like this,
a good citizen should...
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
There!
Ah! This is bad!
Ah...
At a time like this,
what should a good citizen do?
Fool! I know.
Kyaa!
Excuse me!
Is anyone there!? Excuse me!
There you are, Heiji.
Geez, these are heavy!
Ah! Kazuha, take care of this guy.
Eh? Wai... Heiji!
Hey, pretty girl there! Could you stop
staring off into space and call the police?
Eh? Me?
Hurry and call the police!
"Fujimaru"
Excuse me!
Damn!
Bro, leave the rest up to me.
Huh? What are you saying!
Well, it's okay.
Just keep quiet and watch.
Excuse me...
"Kazuo's Wife - Fujimaru Yoshino"
What business do you have with my home?
You live here, right?
Just now there was...
I heard a scream coming from your house.
I figure something must've happened.
Hurry and go inside!
Yes...
Excuse me.
What is it with this guy...
The key's inside...
"Fujimaru Family's Detached House"
Dear!
Hey! You're inside, aren't you?
Who's inside other than your husband?
His Assistant, Hideko-san...
Maybe they're so seriously hurt
they can't answer...
Hey! Dear!
- Um, what sort of...
- Okay!
I'll break down the door!
Huh?
Here goes!
Dear...
Could it be you and Hinako-san were...?
Ah!
Please calm down.
Bro, get an ambulance.
No...
Make that the police.
"Kazuo's Assistant
Nakashima Hideko"
Fujimori Kazuo...
Occupation, Composer.
Yeah.
When your Assistant Nakashima Hideko
and you are working on writing music...
"Beika Police Detective - Moria Masayoshi"
...do you always take the key to
the detached house from the entrance?
What you call "writing music,"
is in reality a delicate thing.
We didn't want to bother anyone.
There was some broken glass on the sofa
that had fallen on Hideko-san.
- Ow!
Bro, don't loiter around so much!
Look you, I was...
Oi! You, schoolboy there!
Yes?
This soccer ball here is yours, isn't it?
Yes.
Fujimaru-san, did this ball
smash into that glass?
Yes...
That's it!
I didn't recall it since it happened so suddenly,
but I think that's probably right.
Hear that?
It's your fault someone died.
- That's wrong...
- Ya got it wrong!
It ain't Bro's fault.
What?
The ball came in from above at this angle,
broke the window and struck against here.
Look, you can tell.
There's traces of the ball here.
And then it lost momentum and stopped here.
How can you say such a thing?!
Take a good look around.
If ya think about it, it'd be impossible for
the ball to come in and hit that glass.
Thing is, the ball not only KO'd a purse snatcher,
it broke through this window.
It didn't have the energy left
to break the glass in that frame as well.
Moreover, the time lag between when
the ball broke the window...
...and when the glass smashed was unusual...
Enough's enough!
What's this "time lag" stuff?
Aside from being some dumb kids,
just who on earth are you?!
You don't know? I'm...
The name's Hattori Heiji.
Around Osaka, I'm kinda known as
the High School Detective.
Detective?
The ones I hate most are detectives!
All they tell you is how great they are
and just what achievements they've made!
Just shut up! It's best to leave
this investigation to us police!
Ah... excuse me!
We should go now.
It's okay, it's okay.
Hey, Detective.
A moment.
He's the son of Police Superintendent Hattori Heizo
of the Osaka Prefecture Police Headquarters?
I didn't know!
I am truly sorry about that!
I'm the MPD's Beika Police Office,
Crime Enforcement Unit...
...Police Sargent Moria Masayoshi!
Ya didn't have ta tell 'im who my father is.
It's okay!
If ya've got it, flaunt it.
Well, whatever.
Ah, let's see.
Bro, what's yer name?
Ah...
You're a detective and you don't know?
This is Kudo...
Ahh! It's To...
Just call me Toiru...
The "To" is like "Toguchi" (door), the "I" like "Italy"
and "ru" like "Nagareru" (to stream or flow),
so it's written as "Toiru."
I'm just an ordinary 2nd year student
at Teitan High School.
Toiru...
That's a rare name, ain't it?
Hmm... Toiru, huh?
Well anyhoo, just leave the rest to me.
If you would please.
Hey, Shin'ichi!
What are you planning?!
What's this "Toiru" thing?
Shh!
This is a rare chance, isn't it?
Perhaps this isn't a coincidence.
I get to take a look at
Osaka's Great Detective.
The soccer ball didn't hit it.
Then, how did the glass
in this frame break...
There's that, ain't there?
That's the question.
Anyhoo, this is a perfect closed room case...
...where all the entrances
and windows were locked.
Could've been set up by someone...
to make us think it was an accident.
Right?
What was that?
Fujimaru-san...
When we rushed up...
...why didn't you open the door right away?
Ya should've answered your wife.
So why didn't ya?
Ah, that was...
I was dumbstruck by
the suddenness of it all.
Look, anyone would...
I see.
But... ya still had time to stop yer music.
What do you mean?
Ready?
After Toiru's ball
broke through this window...
...we heard some really loud music
comin' from this room.
And then a little later...
...we heard the sound of glass breaking.
After Hideko-san's scream,
the music stopped.
I'm asking who stopped it.
Fujimaru-san,
were you the one who stopped it?
I told you, since I was so surprised,
I don't remember!
What's more...
While you were listening to music
turned up that loud...
...how could you possibly be doing
any composing?
That certainly ain't delicate, is it?
That kind of song writing.
That was...
While you were working...
...it's also strange yer Assistant
would be lying down on the sofa.
Fujimaru-san...
...truth is, you and Hideko-san
were on this sofa...
Don't joke around!
Ma'am, you said it when you
saw your husband, didn't you?
"It couldn't be that Hideko-san
and you were..."
Could you tell me?
The meaning of those words.
Enough's enough!
Be quiet!
Yoshino, don't tell them anything!
You don't have to say anything. Right!
Detective, take care of the husband.
Understood!
"Fujimaru Family Main Wing, Living Room"
Here.
Thank you.
I didn't want such an ugly story
to come out like this.
When did ya first notice it?
Your husband and Hideko-san's relationship.
About...
...3 months ago.
I'm sure he had just forgotten
to take in the key.
He was only playing the music that loud
so their affair wouldn't be exposed, wasn't he?
Ma'am, I feel so sorry for ya.
You've been avidly watching him, haven't you?
What? Are you jealous?
Fo... fool! Who's jealous?
Then leave me alone.
Ah... Eh?
Ma'am, is that true?
Yes.
"I'll hurry and break up with her."
I heard him blame Hideko-san for it.
"If she won't, I'll kill her," he said.
A threat, huh...
All right.
Ma'am, it's best if you wait here.
Hey, little Sis there.
Eh? You mean me?
This guy Toiru-kun called you Ran.
That's you, right?
Yes.
Could you come with me for a bit?
Um...
You want something of me?
I'll say this especially, but if ya's makes
a pass at Heiji, I won't keep still about it.
Huh?
Long time ago, me and Heiji were in
a relationship like a "chain of iron."
So if some pretty little thing
thinks she can come along...
...and easily break that chain,
she's got another thing...
Don't worry!
I would never, ever do such a thing.
Rest assured about that.
Then what was that?
You could say he's got an atmosphere
about him similar to the one I think about...
What's that? Are ya saying ya like
a man similar to my Heiji?
No, it's not "like" or anything...
You could say it's more like
being around a detective otaku is...
Ah!
He's like this huge loves-mysteries nut!
Huh? A huge loves-mysteries nut?
Yoshino-san, you helped
compose this too, didn't you?
Yes.
Before we got married,
I was Fujimaru's Assistant.
Then I'm sure you must know
a lot about music, don't you?
Not that much.
Hold on a minute there.
I've never threatened Hideko!
My wife's mistaken...
Anyhow, I wouldn't kill her!
Then what's the reason you didn't
open the door right away?
Like I said...
I told you I don't remember, didn't I!
Could it be you...
Detective, I want to check with
the Coroner about something.
Yes!
That's what I thought.
Yes, thanks.
If you would please.
So long.
"Charm"
Hmm...
So that "chain of iron" was handcuffs, huh?
Yeah.
And I keep this piece from it inside here.
Hmm...
Say, say! Are you two dating?
Ah, no, no!
I'm more like an older sister to Heiji.
More importantly,
how about you, Ran-chan?
Are you and that
huge loves-mysteries nut going out together?
Well, it isn't clear if you could call
our relationship that...
We don't have the
strong bonds you and him have.
Oi! What are you doing?
Who's this "huge loves-mysteries nut"?
I don't know!
More importantly,
have you found something out?
Hattori-kun might settle
this case first, you know.
That's fine; it doesn't matter.
No matter who the detective is...
There is always just one truth.
Geez!
He's such a huge loves-mysteries nut!
Ah, got it.
Hattori-kun, it was just like you said.
According to the Coroner...
...there were many small cuts on the upper part
of the dead person's body from the glass...
...and yet her clothes didn't have
any holes in them.
I figured...
You re-dressed Hideko-san's corpse,
didn't you?
"Hideko-chan."
In order to conceal your relationship
with Hideko-san.
More than anything, you were only
thinking about protecting yourself.
If we had been exposed,
it would have caused a lot of complications...
But you've got to believe me!
I didn't do this!
Then, how did the glass break?
I don't know!
The glass just broke on its own!
I locked the door like always
and played the music...
"Say..."
"...do you hear anything strange?"
"It's just your imagination."
Then I heard this sound like a trembling.
"Kyaa!"
A strange sound...
Like I thought, it was...
Huh? What's that?
Oi, oi, oi, oi!
Who gave you permission to...
I'm MPD Investigation Unit One's
Assistant Inspector, Sato Miwako.
MPD...
Investigation Unit One?!
Please excuse me! Feel free!
When I saw the photo in this room,
I got a strange, discomforting feeling.
Look, this composition is extremely lop-sided.
Moreover, the "No Life" has a period to it.
And, so I thought...
This must be part of a set of photos which
completes an English sentence.
They're like those rival
wind god vs. lighting god pictures.
And there's a wall that's perfect for displaying
just such a frame in the living room.
And there was also a receipt from the store
which had handled the frame.
"Fujimori Kazuo
Modeling Picture Frames"
All that bothered me,
so I called Detective Sato.
Kudo... er, Toiru-kun...
Ah, after hearing about it from Toiru-kun...
...I confirmed with the store that the glass
had been broken and needed to be replaced.
That's incredible, Toiru...
With that, the mystery of this case is solved.
Well, let's do this.
Everyone, watch carefully.
What's this about, Heiji?
I only hear music and no strange sounds,
yet nothing's happening.
What is this?
This should be the way it went down.
That's it...
I guess this is it!
Eh? Why?
Why did you lower the music?
So now everyone, let me show you.
There is just one truth.
Eh?
Is this psychic power again?
Fool!
That couldn't be it, now could it?
Here goes.
It broke...
Why?
You didn't do anything.
Natural frequency...
That's the trick that broke the glass.
Could it be you mean, resonance?
That's right.
All objects have a frequency at which
they naturally tend to vibrate at.
The music being played in this room...
...was set at a frequency at which only
the glass in this frame would vibrate to.
Moreover, the trick was
a speaker hidden behind the photo...
...that was set up to create
the sound at that frequency.
"Sound"?
We didn't hear any sounds, did we?
Yeah.
Such fools...
Anything over 20,000 hertz
and it can't be heard by average people.
But even if people can't hear it, dogs can.
That's why...
It became overly upset and made such a fuss.
To a dog, it was set at an overly high volume.
The glass in that frame
is the same as a swing in a park.
As power is added according to
the movements of each swing...
...the swaying becomes greater.
In the same way...
...the glass gradually became unable to withstand
the specific frequency of those vibrations...
...and so the glass broke.
The criminal, using an invisible weapon,
killed Hideko-san.
And that invisible weapon was...
Resonance.
Wait a minute.
I don't use that frequency.
Thing is, this music has never broken
any glass up until now.
Of course not.
It was someone who knew you were always
playing this music to cover up your affair...
...and who replaced the CD with
this specific frequency included on it.
Right, Toiru?
Yeah.
The criminal is...
...you.
You.
Fujimaru Yoshino-san.
When we entered this room...
...you pretended to stagger back
away from the photo...
...so you could deliberately
turn down the speaker.
Detective.
Check the CD in that deck.
The wife's fingerprints
should be all over it.
Wait!
Yoshino...
Why?
Why would you do such a thing?
It's best if you don't repeat your crimes.
I...
I did everything I could for you until now.
From the time I was your Assistant...
...did you give any thought to who
gave you the idea for that music?
The one who came up with that music was me!
Liar!
I'm the one who originally completed it!
As long as it was of use to you,
I was fine with that.
Because a man like you was in love with me.
But...
...that woman came in here.
"Liar...
You've just decided this by yourself."
"After all, him and me have been tied by
a strong bond for a long time now."
"A bond?"
"Bond"
"That time you caught us?"
"He was the one who chose that music."
The bond I believed was between the two of us...
I was the only one who believed in it.
If my ball hadn't broken the windowpane...
...Kazuo-san would still have been
on that sofa.
Yoshino-san.
Could it be you were trying...
I intended to kill the both of them.
But even if they didn't die
when the glass fell...
...at the very least they'd suffer
serious injuries.
Did the repairs to the frame
come from testing it beforehand?
It was necessary to check the frequency
at which the glass would break.
You've already seen through everything,
haven't you?
Dear...
Please look forward to it.
Because I'll reveal EVERYTHING to the police.
The two of us do have a bond!
Damn woman...
What bond!?
Don't make fun of bonds...
...because they don't come for free!
'Cause they don't come fer free!
You guys had better be careful too, right?
Say, Toiru.
When did ya start gettin'
suspicious about that wife?
Ever since the moment she returned home...
She made a careless remark.
"Dear!"
"Maybe they're so seriously hurt
they can't answer..."
It was as if she already knew something
had happened to the two of them.
Ah, can't take Tokyo lightly.
First there's that Kudo whatshisname
and now this Bro as well.
Ah... That's the thing.
Truth is...
It really is like a swing.
Huh?
If you add power to match the movement...
...it'll further increase its momentum...
...but if you oppose the movement,
the momentum will become smaller.
Right, Toiru-kun?
Right.
AH!
The game's started already!
Kazuha, let's go!
See ya, Ran-chan!
Ahh! Because you didn't do it quick enough,
you failed to confess to him.
I wonder about that guy?
Can't take Osaka's Great Detective lightly.
- Say, Heiji.
- Huh?
Could it be that Toiru-kun is...
Don't say such senseless things.
It's okay, ain't it?
I look forward to our next meeting.
We'll see if he's still going with
that fool alias "Toiru" then.
Shin'ichi!
Glass... Adultery...
Heiji... Ball...
I've got it!
I know what this is!
"Bonds"
Ran, thank you.
I'm worried about the bonds between us...
Let's hurry and go.
- Shin'ichi!
- Ran!
Ran!
Damn!
"Chat Murder Case!"
"A Corpse That Teleports?!"
"This Drama is Fictional"